A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Michael S. Teitelbaum FA681
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Trip and Conference Files, 1972-1980; I
  - MST Trip to Washington, D.C. Re: Immigration to the United States, May 14, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Washington, D.C. Trip -- Immigration Meetings, Population, May 7, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Washington, D.C. Trip -- Immigration and Refugees, April 29, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Population Resource Center Briefing (preparation materials), Apr 24, 1980 (Box 1)
  - American Immigration and Citizenship Conference (Biltmore Hotel, NYC), Apr 24, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Washington, D.C. Trip, Apr 22, 1980 (Box 1)
  - The Pathfinder Fund Meetings (Boston, MA), Apr 16-18, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Population Association of America Annual Meeting (Denver, CO), Apr 9-12, 1980 (Box 1)
  - U.K. Trip -- IPPF and World Fertility Survey, Mar 28-Apr 5, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Migration Conference (Sheraton Centre, NYC), Mar 20, 1980 (Box 1)
  - In Defense of Aliens (Center for Migration Studies Conference, March 1980) -- Conference Paper Corrections (Box 1)
  - Washington, D.C. Trip -- World Bank Seminar (Reston, VA), Jan 16, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Overseas Development Council -- Population in the Year 2000, Nov 1, 1979 (Box 1)
  - India Trip File, Aug 1979 (Box 1)
  - Sri Lanka Conference File, Aug 1979 (Box 1)
  - China Population Discussion (Washington, D.C.), Aug 7, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Africa Trip -- Program Discussion with Ford Foundation Representatives (1/2), May 20-Jun 8, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Africa Trip -- Program Discussion with Ford Foundation Representatives (2/2), May 20-Jun 8, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Trip to Tufts University -- World Population, Apr 10, 1975 (Box 1)
  - UNFPA Meeting Re: Coordination of Population Assistance Projects, Feb 20-21, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Boston Trip (Nov 7-9, 1974) and Istanbul Trip (Nov 11-13, 1974), Nov 1974 (Box 1)
  - Japan Trip, Nov 1974 (Box 1)
  - Conference on Social Science Research on Population and Development (at the Ford Foundation), Oct 29-30, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Persepolis, Tehran Trip, Jun 1-4, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Moscow and Iran Trip, Jun 1974 (Box 2)
  - England Trip, Dec 19, 1973-Jan 1974 (Box 2)
  - U.K./Europe Trips -- Population Meetings, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Subject Files, 1974-1981; II
  - Immigration and Refugees - Meeting to Discuss Report, "A Refugee Education Resource Center in Thailand" (January 18, 1980), 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Meeting on Immigration and Refugees Re: Foundation Wide Immigration Program, Nov 20, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Memo (draft), "Impact of Immigration on Size of U.S. Population", 1980 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Migration -- Ford Foundation Materials -- RGAs, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Migration -- Ford Foundation Materials -- Papers, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Migration Committee Meeting and Meeting Materials, Grant Proposals (October 9, 1980) (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Migration DAP Committee (1/2), 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Migration DAP Committee (2/2), 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Migration DAP -- Working File, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Palmieri, Victor -- Issues Paper Re: Immigration and Refugees (original), Dec 1980 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - Special Foundation Concerns (Ford Foundation) -- Refugees, Indochina, etc., 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - Immigration and Refugees - United Nations -- Economic Policy Council Panel Session (May 4, 1981) -- Immigration Policy Incl. Teitelbaum Article, "Right vs. Right", 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Abortion Committee -- Memoranda Re: Meetings, Proposals, etc., 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) -- 1981 Symposium (Toronto, Canada) -- "Aging from Birth to Death" -- Michael Teitelbaum Articles and AAAS Report and Revision (Box 3)
  - Asia Population Meeting (Spring 1978) -- Memoranda, Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Fertility, Abortion, Family Planning -- Memoranda, Reports, Proposals, 1979 (Box 3)
  - International Division Reorganization and Management, 1980 (Box 3)
  - International Review Group of Social Science Research on Population and Development (IRG) -- Final Report and Follow-On, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Middle East and Africa (established 12/11/1979) -- Ford Foundation Regional Activities, 1978-1980 (Box 3)
  - Military Task Force -- Memoranda, Reports, Background Papers, Meeting Materials, 1981 (Box 3)
  - PPSO Task Force on the Military and Society, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Population Office -- Budgets (incl. Bellagio background papers and population strategy paper) (1/2), 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Population Office -- Budgets (incl. Bellagio background papers and population strategy paper) (2/2), 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - RGAs -- Instructions, Program Related Information, etc., 1979-1981 (Box 3)
  - Thomas, Franklin A. -- Memoranda, Dec 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Trustees Planning Project -- Papers Prepared for the Ford Foundation, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Trustees Planning Project, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Trustees Planning Project -- Incl. "The Hungry, Crowded, Competitive World", 1976 (Box 3)
  - Women in the Military (and W.E.A.L.) -- Proposal and Report, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Women's Project -- Memorandum Re: Project Code, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Women's Programming -- Ford Foundation International Division Activities -- Memoranda, Reports, Proposals, Grant Recommendations (RGAs) (1/4), 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Women's Programming -- Ford Foundation International Division Activities -- Memoranda, Reports, Proposals, Grant Recommendations (RGAs) (2/4), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Women's Programming -- Ford Foundation International Division Activities -- Memoranda, Reports, Proposals, Grant Recommendations (RGAs) (3/4), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Women's Programming -- Ford Foundation International Division Activities -- Memoranda, Reports, Proposals, Grant Recommendations (RGAs) (4/4), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Women's Programming -- Expanded Programs Memorandum and Ford Foundation Division Statements Re: Women's Programs for Board of Trustees Meeting in March, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Women's Program Group -- Meeting Minutes and Notes, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Workshops -- Population Office (Miscellaneous), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - World Population Year -- Bucharest Conference, 1974 (Box 4)
  - World Population Year -- Bucharest Conference -- "Action Pak", 1974 (Box 4)
- Reports, Speeches, 1972-1981; III
  - Report on Visit to Pakistan (August 14-24, 1972) -- Memorandum from Lyle Saunders, Aug 23, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Speech Materials (general talk on the Ford Foundation and Population) -- Incl. Ford Foundation Reprint on Population and Development, 1974 (Box 4)
  - "Office for Latin America and the Caribbean Program Review and Funding Request for Fiscal Year 1980-1981", Jun 1979 (Box 4)
  - "Population in the 1980s" Information Paper, Dec 1979 (Box 4)
  - "Ford Foundation Programs for Women - An Information Paper for the Board of Trustees", Dec 1979 (Box 4)
  - "Proposals for General Reserve Funding" for Board of Trustees Meeting, Mar 27-28, 1980 (Box 4)
  - "Ford Foundation Programs for Women: Plans and Budgets for Fiscal Years 1980-1981", Mar 1980 (Box 4)
  - "Right vs. Right: Immigration and Refugee Policy in the United States" by Michael S. Teitelbaum, Aug 1, 1980 (Box 4)
  - "Evaluation of the African American Institute (AAI)" -- Memorandum from Melvin Fox, Aug 1980 (Box 4)
  - "The Incidence of State and Local Taxes Under Fiscal Change: Methodology" by Dennis de Tray, Prepared by Rand for the Ford Foundation, Aug 1980 (Box 4)
  - "Exploring a Possible Foundation Program on Nutrition and Related Health Problems", Sep 1980 (Box 4)
  - "Trends and Prospects in World Population" by Michael Teitelbaum, Prepared for the AAAS Workshop, Nov 1980 (Box 4)
  - Expanded Programs for Women -- Reports Re: Ford Foundation Women's Programming (incl. reports from National Affairs Program and Education and Public Policy), 1980 (Box 4)
  - "The Demographic Impact of Tubectomy in Bangladesh" by Anthony R. Measham, et al., [1980] (Box 4)
  - Nutrition/Health Paper, "Child Survival: A Fair Start for Children", Apr 15, 1981 (Box 4)
  - "Fiscal Restraints and the Burden of Local and State Taxes" Prepared by Rand for the Ford Foundation, Apr 1981 (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation Division/Program Concept Papers (Youth, Education, International Affairs, Human Rights and Justice, Governance and Public Policy), 1981 (Box 4)
  - "The Hungry, Crowded, Competitive World - Analytic Commentary" by Michael S. Teitelbaum, et al., n.d. (Box 4)